Welcome to the bank robbery capital of America.
The Town is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Ben Affleck.
Doug MacRay is a longtime thief, who, smarter than the rest of his
crew, is looking for his chance to exit the game.
When a bank job leads to the group kidnapping an attractive branch manager, he takes on the role of monitoring her – but their
burgeoning relationship threatens to unveil the identities of Doug and his crew to the FBI Agent who is on their case.
Doug MacRay, played by Ben Affleck.
James "Jem" Coughlin, played by Jeremy Renner.
Claire Keesey, played by Rebecca Hall.
FBI S.A. Adam Frawley, played by Jon Hamm.
Krista Coughlin, played by Blake Lively.
Albert "Gloansy" Magloan, played by George Carroll.
The Town is a 2010 American neo-noir crime thriller film co-written and directed by
Ben Affleck, adapted from Chuck Hogan's 2004 novel Prince of Thieves.
The film stars Affleck, Rebecca Hall, Jon Hamm, Jeremy Renner, Blake Lively,
Titus Welliver, Pete Postlethwaite, Chris Cooper and Slaine.
It features a Boston bank robber who begins to develop romantic feelings for a victim
of one of his previous robberies but he hides his identity from her.
Meanwhile, he and his crew set out to get one
final score by robbing Fenway Park.
The Town premiered at the Venice Film Festival on September 8, 2010,
and was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures on September 17, 2010.
Based on actual events, the film received positive reviews from critics for its direction, screenplay,
editing, and the performances of the cast (particularly Renner) and grossed $154 million worldwide.
It received various accolades, including the National Board of Review Award for Best Cast, as well as Best Supporting
Actor nominations at the Academy, Golden Globe, SAG (Renner), and BAFTA Awards (Postlethwaite, posthumously).
The film was also honoured as one of the top ten films
of 2010 by the National Board of Review.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, based on novel or book,
ambulance, boston, massachusetts, money laundering.
The tone is emotional and intense.